http://www.ptdiocese.org/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy
We take your privacy seriously.
What personal data we collect and why we collect it.
1. Forms
Throughout our website, we have forms that allow you to send information to us to help guide you in a directed way. These forms help us correspond with you. Your form is not stored in the website database but is forwarded to the email account of the person that will best help you. Your information is never sold or distributed.
When you subscribe to our newsletters we collect only your email address so that we can correspond with you. Your email address is not stored in our website database but is placed in our Mailchimp database (the application we use to send our newsletters and campaigns) for the mass emails we distribute to people who have opted in. You can always request that we remove your email from these lists, or “unsubscribe” from the bottom of the email itself.
2. Google Analytics
We use Google Analytics to track visitors on this site. Google Analytics uses cookies to collect this data. In order to be compliant with the new regulation, Google included a data processing amendment. The data we collect will be processed anonymously and “Data sharing” is disabled. We don’t use other Google services in combination with Google Analytics cookies.
3. Mailchimp
We use Mailchimp for our newsletters and campaigns Mailchimp is one of the best marketing and email automation services available and is GDPR compliant. They have a campaign builder that makes it easy to create email templates. In Mailchimp, we store only your email address provided to the Church and the School when you opted in. If you need to be removed from the list, please contact us or “unsubscribe” from the bottom of the email.
Cookies and Online Tracking
If you leave a comment on our site, you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment.
If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.
How long we retain your data
If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
What rights you have over your data
If you have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. Requests must be made within five days of the comment made, as comments are usually deleted within that timeframe. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.
Security
To protect your personal information, we take reasonable precautions and follow industry best practices to make sure it is not inappropriately lost, misused, accessed, disclosed, altered or destroyed.
We take great measures to make sure our site is secure and routinely scan for malicious injections into our site.
Links to other Websites
Our website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites of interest easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our website, we do not have any control over those other websites. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide while visiting such websites and such websites are not governed by this Privacy Policy. You should exercise caution and be familiar with the privacy policies of any other websites that you visit.
Changes to the privacy policy
We reserve the right to modify this privacy policy at any time, so please review it frequently. Changes and clarifications will take effect immediately upon their posting on the website. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here that it has been updated, so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we use and/or disclose it.
Find
Directories
Offices & Ministries
Cemeteries
Priests
Permanent Deacons
Seminarians
Pastoral Center Staff
